<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Rick Lancee | design student, geek and front-end enthusiast</title>
    <description>I&#39;m a design student, geek and front-end enthusiast. I&#39;m mainly interested in design, progressive web apps and front-end tooling.
</description>
    <link>http://localhost:3000/</link>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:3000/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
    <pubDate>Mon, 06 Jun 2016 21:16:13 +0200</pubDate>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 06 Jun 2016 21:16:13 +0200</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>Jekyll v2.5.1</generator>
    
      <item>
        <title>Prairietorrium</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;For a class project we created a memory game where users had to remember where a prairie dog – the animal we chose – came out of his hole in the ground. The goal was to increase awareness and engagement of “hidden” animals. Animals that were not very popular with the general audience. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;video autoplay=&quot;true&quot; loop=&quot;true&quot;&gt;
    &lt;source src=&quot;http://localhost:3000/assets/images/prairietorrium/popup.mp4&quot; type=&quot;video/mp4&quot; /&gt;
&lt;/video&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;User would have to remember that holes where the prairie dog came out of to continue&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The game constisted of 6 level which increased in difficulty each level on wards. It had a minimal requirement of two people. People played against each other and the person who was fastest would win.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Each level that you progress though you would move up a step in a virtual arena, you won if the reached the top. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
    &lt;img src=&quot;http://localhost:3000/assets/images/prairietorrium/levels.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;The different levels&quot; /&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;The different levels in the game&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 06 Jun 2016 00:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:3000/case/prairietorrium</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:3000/case/prairietorrium</guid>
        
        
        <category>case</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Overwatch Timeline</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://ricklancee.github.io/overwatch-timeline/&quot;&gt;http://ricklancee.github.io/overwatch-timeline/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;video autoplay=&quot;true&quot; loop=&quot;true&quot;&gt;
    &lt;source src=&quot;http://localhost:3000/assets/images/overwatch/timeline.mp4&quot; type=&quot;video/mp4&quot; /&gt;
&lt;/video&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As an excercise i created an interactive time line about the story of the game &lt;a href=&quot;http://playoverwatch.com&quot;&gt;overwatch&lt;/a&gt;. My goal here was to create a interactive experience at 60 frames per second in the browser. Using techniques like a &lt;a href=&quot;https://developer.mozilla.org/en-US/docs/Games/Anatomy&quot;&gt;game loop&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;http://codepen.io/rachsmith/post/animation-tip-lerp&quot;&gt;lerping&lt;/a&gt; for the animations.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I managed to achieve my goal of 60 frame per second by using the performant css and javacript techniques. The javascript only function is to calculate some numbers about where u are and where you need to go. It only sets the only DOM interaction is setting a &lt;code&gt;transform&lt;/code&gt; attribute on the container.   &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The demo works great in Google Chrome but in other browsers not so much. In IE or Edge it doesn’t work at all, and in firefox the scrolling is really slow. However it was not my intent to create a cross browser experience it would have been nice it worked across all major browsers. &lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sun, 05 Jun 2016 00:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:3000/case/overwatch-timeline</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:3000/case/overwatch-timeline</guid>
        
        
        <category>case</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Darkest Nights</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Darkest nights was a short horror minigame that we (Bart van Dongen, Wesley Hölzel and me) made during a 3 day game design cource at school. After some brainstorming we came up with the idea to make a horror game.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
    &lt;img src=&quot;http://localhost:3000/assets/images/darkestnights/txt.png&quot; alt=&quot;The introduction text of the game&quot; /&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;This intro text of the game&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the game you are “Tet”, who is looking for his teddy bear, “Teddy” in the middle of the night. Since teddy is still a litle kid everything looks scary in the dark and his imagination runs wild. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The game itself is pretty basic, on each level Teddy is hidden and you have to find him in complete darkness. After each level it will become harder, the rooms will be bigger and there are more monsters to look out for.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The monsters in the game can be stunned by shining your flashlight on them if your close, but they will continue to move a short time after you go away. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;video autoplay=&quot;true&quot; loop=&quot;true&quot;&gt;
    &lt;source src=&quot;http://localhost:3000/assets/images/darkestnights/nights.mp4&quot; type=&quot;video/mp4&quot; /&gt;
&lt;/video&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;An enemy stuned by the flashlight&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The game was really fun to make, Bart did the artwork in the game which game out really nice and Me and Wesley did most of the programming of the game. The game was quite a success because people who played it were genuinely scared.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sat, 04 Jun 2016 00:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:3000/case/darkest-nights</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:3000/case/darkest-nights</guid>
        
        
        <category>case</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Explore Amsterdam</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Explore Amsterdam was for an school project where the students had to design an app or website that used the information of the Internation Student Guide of amsterdam. After a concepting process my idea was to create an app where users would be presented with a set of cards. On these cards where places of interest that the user could visit. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;video autoplay=&quot;true&quot; loop=&quot;true&quot;&gt;
    &lt;source src=&quot;http://localhost:3000/assets/images/explore/explore.mp4&quot; type=&quot;video/mp4&quot; /&gt;
&lt;/video&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;The application in use&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Places supposed to ranked based on location so relevant nearby places would be on the top of the card stack. However due to time contstraits and i was not able to include location based cards. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The application itself was really fun to make, cards where swipable on mobile so you could dismiss them. You could favorite cards so you can find them later on again. One issue was that the library i used for swiping was nice, but it did not allow me to do certain animation that i would have like to incorperate into the app. Such as the card expanding on click. Next time however i will not opt for using a library, but rather create my own to solve the problem. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Working demo: &lt;a href=&quot;https://ricklancee.github.io/explore-amsterdam/&quot;&gt;https://ricklancee.github.io/explore-amsterdam/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 03 Jun 2016 00:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:3000/case/explore-amsterdam</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:3000/case/explore-amsterdam</guid>
        
        
        <category>case</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>BUDDY an E-Health app</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;You’ll find this post in your &lt;code&gt;_posts&lt;/code&gt; directory. Go ahead and edit it and re-build the site to see your changes. You can rebuild the site in many different ways, but the most common way is to run &lt;code&gt;jekyll serve&lt;/code&gt;, which launches a web server and auto-regenerates your site when a file is updated.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jun 2016 00:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:3000/case/buddy</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:3000/case/buddy</guid>
        
        
        <category>case</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>MOTI a Motivation App</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/oGuEnXagr-U&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Bla bla bla content…&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 30 May 2016 00:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:3000/case/sporters</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:3000/case/sporters</guid>
        
        
        <category>case</category>
        
      </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
