<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Rick Lancee | Design student, geek and front-end enthusiast</title>
    <description>I&#39;m a design student, geek and front-end enthusiast. I&#39;m mainly interested in design, progressive web apps and front-end tooling.
</description>
    <link>https://ricklancee.github.io/ricklancee.io/</link>
    <atom:link href="https://ricklancee.github.io/ricklancee.io/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
    <pubDate>Tue, 07 Jun 2016 13:16:08 +0200</pubDate>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 07 Jun 2016 13:16:08 +0200</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>Jekyll v2.5.1</generator>
    
      <item>
        <title>Prairietorrium</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;For a class project we created a memory game where users had to remember where a prairie dog – the animal we chose – came out of his hole in the ground. The goal was to increase awareness and engagement of “hidden” animals. Animals that were not very popular with the general audience. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;video autoplay=&quot;true&quot; loop=&quot;true&quot;&gt;
    &lt;source src=&quot;https://ricklancee.github.io/ricklancee.io/assets/images/prairietorrium/popup.mp4&quot; type=&quot;video/mp4&quot; /&gt;
&lt;/video&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;User would have to remember that holes where the prairie dog came out of to continue&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The game consisted  of 6 levels which increased in difficulty each level. It had a minimal requirement of two people. People played against each other and the fastest person won. Each level that you progress though you would move up a step in a virtual arena, you won when you reach the top. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
    &lt;img src=&quot;https://ricklancee.github.io/ricklancee.io/assets/images/prairietorrium/levels.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;The different levels&quot; /&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;The different levels in the game&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 06 Jun 2016 00:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
        <link>https://ricklancee.github.io/ricklancee.io/case/prairietorrium</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://ricklancee.github.io/ricklancee.io/case/prairietorrium</guid>
        
        
        <category>case</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Overwatch Timeline</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://ricklancee.github.io/overwatch-timeline/&quot;&gt;http://ricklancee.github.io/overwatch-timeline/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;video autoplay=&quot;true&quot; loop=&quot;true&quot;&gt;
    &lt;source src=&quot;https://ricklancee.github.io/ricklancee.io/assets/images/overwatch/timeline.mp4&quot; type=&quot;video/mp4&quot; /&gt;
&lt;/video&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As an exercise i created an interactive time line about the story of the game &lt;a href=&quot;http://playoverwatch.com&quot;&gt;overwatch&lt;/a&gt;. My goal here was to create a interactive experience at 60 frames per second in the browser. Using techniques like a &lt;a href=&quot;https://developer.mozilla.org/en-US/docs/Games/Anatomy&quot;&gt;game loop&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;http://codepen.io/rachsmith/post/animation-tip-lerp&quot;&gt;lerping&lt;/a&gt; for the animations.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I managed to achieve my goal of 60 frame per second by using the performant css and javacript. The Javascript has only one purpose; to calculate numbers about where you currently are, and where you need to go. The only DOM interaction is setting a &lt;code&gt;transform&lt;/code&gt; attribute on the container. Which results in smooth animations.   &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The demo works great in Google Chrome but in other browsers not so much. In IE or Edge it doesn’t work at all, and in firefox the scrolling is really slow. However it was not my intent to create a cross browser experience it would have been nice it worked across all major browsers. — but it would have been nice.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sun, 05 Jun 2016 00:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
        <link>https://ricklancee.github.io/ricklancee.io/case/overwatch-timeline</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://ricklancee.github.io/ricklancee.io/case/overwatch-timeline</guid>
        
        
        <category>case</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Darkest Nights</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Darkest nights was a short horror mini-game that we (Bart van Dongen, Wesley Hölzel and me) made during a 3 day game design program at school. After some brainstorming we came up with the idea to make a horror game.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
    &lt;img src=&quot;https://ricklancee.github.io/ricklancee.io/assets/images/darkestnights/txt.png&quot; alt=&quot;The introduction text of the game&quot; /&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;This intro text of the game&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the game you are “Tet”, who is looking for his teddy bear, “Teddy” in the middle of the night. Since teddy is still a little kid everything looks scary in the dark and his imagination runs wild. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The game itself is pretty basic, on each level Teddy is hidden and you have to find him in complete darkness. After each level it will become harder, the rooms will be bigger and there are more monsters to look out for.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The monsters in the game can be stunned by shining your flashlight on them if your close, but they will continue to move a short time after you go away. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;video autoplay=&quot;true&quot; loop=&quot;true&quot;&gt;
    &lt;source src=&quot;https://ricklancee.github.io/ricklancee.io/assets/images/darkestnights/nights.mp4&quot; type=&quot;video/mp4&quot; /&gt;
&lt;/video&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;An enemy stunned by the flashlight&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The game was really fun to make, Bart did the artwork in the game which turned out really nice, and Me and Wesley did most of the programming. The game was quite a success because people who played it were genuinely scared.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sat, 04 Jun 2016 00:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
        <link>https://ricklancee.github.io/ricklancee.io/case/darkest-nights</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://ricklancee.github.io/ricklancee.io/case/darkest-nights</guid>
        
        
        <category>case</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Explore Amsterdam</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Explore Amsterdam was for an school project where the students had to design an app or website that used the information of the International Student Guide of Amsterdam. After a “concepting” process my idea was to create an app where users would be presented with a set of cards. On these cards where places of interest that the user could visit. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;video autoplay=&quot;true&quot; loop=&quot;true&quot;&gt;
    &lt;source src=&quot;https://ricklancee.github.io/ricklancee.io/assets/images/explore/explore.mp4&quot; type=&quot;video/mp4&quot; /&gt;
&lt;/video&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;The application in use&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Places supposed to ranked based on location so relevant nearby places would be on the top of the card stack. However due to time constraints and I was not able to include location based cards. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The application itself was really fun to make, cards where swipeable on mobile so you could dismiss them. You could favourite cards so you can find them later on again. One issue was that the library I used for swiping was nice, but it did not allow me to do certain animation that I would have like to incorporate into the app. Such as the card expanding on click. Next time however i will not opt for using a library, but rather create my own to solve the problem. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Working demo: &lt;a href=&quot;https://ricklancee.github.io/explore-amsterdam/&quot;&gt;https://ricklancee.github.io/explore-amsterdam/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 03 Jun 2016 00:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
        <link>https://ricklancee.github.io/ricklancee.io/case/explore-amsterdam</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://ricklancee.github.io/ricklancee.io/case/explore-amsterdam</guid>
        
        
        <category>case</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>BUDDY an E-Health app</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Buddy is an app we created with 4 students. The goal of the app was to support patients of a chronic illness in their lives. As a group we chose to make an app for people with Social Anxiety Disorder. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We went trough a couple of iteration of the application and in the end we decided we would focus on a type of cognitive therapy called guided imagery.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Our app was indented to help with the at home therapy process. Users would use our app in combination with E-sensors that measure heart rate and breathing. You would use the app to give you feedback during your therapy sessions. The app would give you bio-feedback which tells you if you were getting stressed or not.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
    &lt;img src=&quot;https://ricklancee.github.io/ricklancee.io/assets/images/buddy/FLOWCHART.png&quot; alt=&quot;The flowchart of the application&quot; /&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;The flowchart of the application&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The final product didn’t include actual sensors, these were faked for the demonstration. I would have liked to include these sensors in a working prototype however due to time constraints this was not possible. In the end i learned a lot from the prototyping tool Flinto, which helped us prototype the animations for the final product.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;video autoplay=&quot;true&quot; loop=&quot;true&quot;&gt;
    &lt;source src=&quot;https://ricklancee.github.io/ricklancee.io/assets/images/buddy/buddy.mp4&quot; type=&quot;video/mp4&quot; /&gt;
&lt;/video&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;An animation demo of the onboarding process&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Working demo: &lt;a href=&quot;https://tevinstuurland.github.io/e-health-app/&quot;&gt;https://tevinstuurland.github.io/e-health-app/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jun 2016 00:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
        <link>https://ricklancee.github.io/ricklancee.io/case/buddy</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://ricklancee.github.io/ricklancee.io/case/buddy</guid>
        
        
        <category>case</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>MOTI a Motivation App</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;The MOTI app was an mobile app that helped Olympic rowers stay connected an motivated with their teammates and coach. The goal of the app was to create something that would benefit Olympic athletes in journey towards the Olympics.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
    &lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/oGuEnXagr-U&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;The MOTI product video&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We wanted to create a simple application, one that was easy to use and didn’t have too much complexity. We opted for only 3 main screens, the homescreen where users could see how the rest of the team was doing, a profile screen where users could see their own data and a chat screen where the coach and athletes could keep in touch with each other.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
    &lt;img src=&quot;https://ricklancee.github.io/ricklancee.io/assets/images/moti/screens.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;The main screens of the application&quot; /&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;The main screens of the application&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Everyday the athletes have to write down certain pieces of data about themselves. We as a team wanted to use this data in our application. In our final prototype users of the app would be prompted daily to input their data. However in a real world application this data could be transmitted through certain devices like a heart rate sensor.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;video autoplay=&quot;true&quot; loop=&quot;true&quot;&gt;
    &lt;source src=&quot;https://ricklancee.github.io/ricklancee.io/assets/images/moti/gegevens.mp4&quot; type=&quot;video/mp4&quot; /&gt;
&lt;/video&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Filling in daily data&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The coach of the team could keep in touch and check up on the data of his team. He could decide if things were going OK, or when things were going poorly. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;video autoplay=&quot;true&quot; loop=&quot;true&quot;&gt;
    &lt;source src=&quot;https://ricklancee.github.io/ricklancee.io/assets/images/moti/messages.mp4&quot; type=&quot;video/mp4&quot; /&gt;
&lt;/video&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Coach messages are displayed on the homescreen&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Working demo: http://ricklancee.github.io/moti-app/&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 30 May 2016 00:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
        <link>https://ricklancee.github.io/ricklancee.io/case/sporters</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://ricklancee.github.io/ricklancee.io/case/sporters</guid>
        
        
        <category>case</category>
        
      </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
